Finn Thompson

nnifinn@gmail.com
Seattle, WA
finnthompson.me

I am a developer, UX designer, and technical writer with a passion for delivering excellent user-focused solutions. I have programmed as a hobby for 8+ years while cultivating a user-focused mentality through my education. I have experience developing software with Java, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Python, React, and more.

Education

University of Washington B.S. in Human Centered Design and Engineering GPA: 3.65 overall, 3.8 in major

Sept. 2014 - June 2018

Experience

Shift Supervisor, Starbucks

Seattle, WA

Seattle, WA

Empowered a team of baristas to deliver exceptional customer experiences

Oct. 2016 - Dec. 2018

Sustained customer ratings as one of the top stores in its district

• Voted Partner of the Quarter by my team in Summer 2016 as a barista

Research Intern, Scripps Translational Science Institute

La Jolla, CA

Developed a Java GUI application to save researchers time identifying gene relationships

May 2014 - June 2014

Designed a term frequency-inverse document frequency algorithm to rank results

Developer / Project Lead, RuneDream

Reno, NV

• Designed and developed a Java application to automate gameplay of the game RuneScape

Jan. 2012 - May 2013

• Created a website and forum to deliver and support the application with 50k+ downloads

Projects

Smart Pill Box Team Capstone

Python, Research

- Designed and developed a smart opioid prescription management device
- Assembled and soldered Arduino and Raspberry Pi prototypes
- Developed C and Python code to power the device and its touchscreen UI
- Led a usability research study to evaluate the first iteration of the prototype

Netflix Gamepad Interface Plugin

JavaScript, UI/UX

• Chrome extension providing an intuitive interface for controlling Netflix with a gamepad

Various JavaScript Libraries with Documentation

JavaScript, Tech Writing

- Developed FormPersistence.js, a library for persisting form data across refreshes or sessions
- Developed Gamepads.js, a library offering expanded HTML5 gamepad support
- Co-developed pseudo:styler, a library for toggling CSS pseudo class styles on elements

UW Course Seat Claimer

Java, UI/UX

 Java GUI application that listens to a user's email inbox for open seat notifications on full classes and registers the user for the open seat, dropping conflicted courses if specified

Skills / Activities

Programming: Java, JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, Regex, React, jQuery, SQL, Chrome extensions Technologies: Git, Markdown, VSCode, IntelliJ, Windows, Ubuntu, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Figma

Holistic Skills: UX design, English/technical writing, teamwork and communication

Stack Overflow (23k+ reputation), GitHub (15+ repositories) Online Activity: